sportingcharts.com 2019-12-06

# SportingCharts.com | Privacy Policy

Thank you for visiting SportingCharts.com. As a guest to our site, your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy, this notice has been posted to explain our online information practices and the way your information is collected and used at this site.

### Information Collection and Use

On [SportingCharts.com](https://www.sportingcharts.com/), you may enter contests, vote in surveys, submit demographic information, participate in one of our online forums, subscribe to services such as our e-newsletters, and express opinions. The types of personally identifiable information that may be collected via one or more of these vehicles include name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, fax number, credit card information, demographic information, and information about your interests and use of various products, programs, and services.

[SportingCharts.com](https://www.sportingcharts.com/) may also collect certain non-personally identifiable information when you visit many of our Web pages such as the type of operating system you are using (e.g. Windows XP, Macintosh OSX), the type of browser you are using (e.g. Internet Explorer, Mozilla Firefox), and the domain name of your Internet service provider (e.g. America Online, MSN, Earthlink).

[SportingCharts.com](https://www.sportingcharts.com/) and its parent company, Sporting Charts Inc., is the sole owner of the information collected on this site. We will not sell, share, or rent e-mail address to other parties in any way other than what is disclosed in this privacy statement.

### Electronic Newsletters

You can choose to subscribe to one or all of our FREE electronic newsletters. To subscribe, simply check the box for each newsletter you wish you receive, provide your email address and other requested information then submit. From time to time, as a subscriber to our newsletter, you are eligible to receive promotions from SportingCharts.com, our affiliates and trusted partners. You can always remove yourself from our newsletter e-mail lists by simply following the "Unsubscribe" directions included in each newsletter you receive.

### Collection of Information by Third-Party Sites and Sponsors

This site may contain links to other sites whose information practices may be different than ours. Visitors should consult the privacy notices of these other sites as we have no control over information that is submitted to, or collected by, these third parties.

This site may contain advertising, forms and other data collection methods that directly generate information for sponsors. Data collected by other parties will be identified by the sponsors' name and/or logo. This site has no control over the third-party sponsors' use of this information.

This site may offer contests, sweepstakes, or promotions that are sponsored by or co-sponsored with identified third parties. By virtue of their sponsorship, these third parties may obtain personally identifiable information that visitors voluntarily submit to participate in the contest, sweepstakes, or promotion. This site has no control over the third-party sponsors' use of this information.

Some of [SportingCharts.com](https://www.sportingcharts.com/) advertisers covered by this Privacy Notice may use a reputable third party to present or serve the advertisements that you may see at its Web pages. These third party ad servers may use cookies, web beacons, clear .gifs or similar technologies to help present such advertisements, and to help measure and research the advertisements' effectiveness. The use of these technologies by these third party ad servers is subject to their own privacy policies and is not covered by our privacy policy.

### Cookies

To enhance your experience on [SportingCharts.com](https://www.sportingcharts.com/), many of our Web pages use "cookies." Cookies are text files we place in your computer's browser to store your preferences. Cookies, by themselves, do not tell us your e-mail address or other personally identifiable information unless you choose to provide this information to us by, for example, registering at one of our sites. However, once you choose to furnish the site with personally identifiable information, this information may be linked to the data stored in the cookie.

We use cookies to understand site usage and to improve the content and offerings on our site. For example, we may use cookies to personalize your experience at our web pages (e.g. to recognize you by name when you return to our site), and save your password in password-protected areas. We also may use cookies to offer you products, programs, or services.

"Web beacons" or clear .gifs are small pieces of code placed on a web page to monitor the behaviour and collect data about the visitors viewing a web page. For example, web beacons can be used to count the users who visit a web page or to deliver a cookie to the browser of a visitor viewing that page. We may use web beacons on this site from time to time for this and other purposes.

### Sharing

We will share aggregated demographic information with our partners and advertisers. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person.

### Security

This site takes every precaution to protect our users' information. When users submit sensitive information via the Web site, your information is protected both online and off-line.

When our registration/order form asks users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number and/or social security number), that information is encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry - SSL. While on a secure page, such as our order form, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Mozilla Firefox and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when you are just 'surfing'.

While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line. All of our users' information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job are granted access to personally identifiable information. In addition, the servers that we store personally identifiable information on are kept in a secure environment.

If you have any questions about the security at our Web site, you can send an e-mail to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#fd9c99909493bdae8d928f8994939abe959c8f898ed39e9290).

### Supplementation of Information

In order for this Web site to properly fulfill its obligation to our customers, it may be necessary to supplement the information collected from this site with other information owned by this site's parent company or third-party information. In order for this Web site to enhance its ability to tailor the site to an individual's preference, we combine information about the purchasing habits of users with similar information from our partners.

### Correcting and Updating Personal Information

If a user's personally identifiable information changes (such as your zip code), or if a user no longer desires our service, we will endeavour to provide a way to correct, update or remove that user's personal data provided to us. 

### Notification of Changes to This Policy

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post a notification of such change on our home page. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users of such intentions via e-mail. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.

If you feel that this company is not abiding by its posted privacy policy, please send an e-mail to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#d7b6b3babeb997a4a7b8a5a3beb9b0b4bfb6a5a3a4f9b4b8ba)

Last updated on November 1st, 2011
